Yuvaraj Thiagarajan

Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for building developer friendly APIs and user friendly UIs that solve challenging engineering problems

(650) 931-5371

yuvaraj.name@gmail.com

http://yuvaraj.name

EXPERIENCE

Sumo Logic, Inc. (Formerly FactorChain, Inc.) Redwood City, CA - *Senior Software Engineer*

MARCH 2017 - JULY 2018

Built enhancements for web application responsible for Security Investigations.

REST API enhancements for improved performance: Implemented support for batching multiple similar API requests into a single REST HTTP request and REST API Expansion to combine the responses of multiple API endpoints into a single endpoint to avoid the number of HTTP requests for the resource requested.

<u>Unified APIs and UI:</u> Worked on unifying FactorChain's Security Investigation webapp with the Sumo Logic webapp after acquisition of FactorChain by Sumo Logic, Inc. This involved migrating the Python and Django powered REST APIs, React/Redux powered UI to share the application state with Angular app and rewriting the whole UI test suite using Jest and Enzyme.

<u>Tech</u>: JavaScript ES6, Python, React, Redux, Django, Webpack, NPM, REST, HTML, CSS, Jest, Enzyme

IAC Search and Media, Inc., Oakland, CA - Node.js Developer

DECEMBER 2014 - JANUARY 2017

Led the efforts to build Price History trend graphs for shopping websites of IAC Led the team from design to production to deliver price history trend graphs for shopping sites of IAC. I built the Node.js microservice backend that performs:

- Efficient retrieval of meta info for the products from the PriceGrabber feed and the price history info for the retrieved products from the REST web service using Async.js library.
- 2) Perform a series of mathematical calculations on the numbers obtained from the web services using Lodash and present the results to the client

Designed and developed Sticky Notes

Developed a server-less note-taking JavaScript application in React that helps users to create, edit, and display notes stored in Amazon DynamoDB. React, Draft.js, Redux, Webpack, Jest along with Less, Lodash, HTML5 and CSS3 are used in the frontend and Amazon Web Services were used in the backend.

SUMMARY

13 years of professional full stack development experience

Experience in building high throughput scalable REST and GraphQL microservices

Experience in building user friendly single page applications

Experience in data modeling for both SQL and NoSQL databases

SKILLS

Software Architectures:

REST, GraphQL, SPA, Microservices, Serverless

Programming Languages:

JavaScript, Python, PHP, Go

Web Technologies:

Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Apollo, Prisma, graphql-yoga, Django, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Webpack, Lodash

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, SQLite

Platform: GNU/Linux, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes

CDK Global, Inc, Pleasanton, CA - Software Engineer III

AUGUST 2013 - DECEMBER 2014

Built Ad Network Channel Service

Designed and developed a REST API to encapsulate the differences among multiple Ad Network Platforms so that the in-house ad server apps can communicate with a consistent REST web service.

Implemented Ad Impression Cost Logging

Designed and developed a feature for the in-house ad server to obtain and log the aggregated cost for ad impressions from different ad networks to the ad server logs and database.

Tech: PHP, PostgreSQL, Zend Framework

R Systems, Inc, Mountain View, CA - Senior PHP Engineer

APRIL 2013 - AUGUST 2013

Implemented scalable and extensible REST API to manage the configuration of portable cloud storage devices through smartphones and other mobile devices.

<u>Tech</u>: PHP, Zend Framework, SQLite, Shell Scripts, Apache, Lighttpd, Linux.

Shutterfly, Inc, Redwood City, CA - Senior Web Engineer

NOVEMBER 2012 - APRIL 2013

Developed an online greeting card personalizer

Implemented a feature for enabling users to navigate through the different surfaces of greeting cards, and presenting the users with different views of folded surfaces depending on whether the user is in Edit or Preview mode.

<u>Tech</u>: Java, Spring, JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Backbone, SASS/Compass

Webroot, Inc., San Mateo, CA - *Web Applications Developer, SaaS*JANUARY 2010 - SEPTEMBER 2012

Built high-performance and scalable REST APIs

Built the back-end architecture for REST based JSON web service APIs to be consumed by Android/iOS mobile devices. Implemented a custom ORM solution for database abstraction with memcache support optimized for read performance to enable rapidly growing number of concurrent connections.

Tech: PHP, Zend Framework, MySQL, Memcache, Gearman, Apache HTTP, Nginx Developed a Single Page Application for Mobile Device Management

Involved in the design and development of Web Portal for Mobile Security and Mobile Device Management. The web application was designed to be a Single Page Application (SPA) using the architectural patterns of MVC and REST.

Tech: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, Zend Framework, MySQL, Apache

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer and Information Sciences with a major in Information Systems at University of South Alabama (2005)

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science at University of Madras (2002)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Portfolio Website: Built a site containing my resume, personal projects and my blog using Python, Django, PostgreSQL and Bootstrap live at http://yuvaraj.name

Slack Rover - Serverless Note taking app in Slack:

I implemented a serverless note taking app within Slack to help users save and fetch useful notes from Slack channels on demand as part of a two day hackathon project in my previous employment. The data is stored in the Amazon DynamoDB, the **REST API endpoints** implemented in API Gateway, the logic of the app is implemented as AWS Lambda functions and access control was implemented through AWS IAM roles.

Distributed Dictionary:

Built a distributed dictionary application to demonstrate the power of Go's concurrency model.

Array Networks, Inc., Milpitas, CA - Software Engineer

MARCH 2006 - AUGUST 2009

Built a JavaScript library

Implemented an object-oriented JavaScript library to enable external client-side scripts to achieve asynchronous communication with the server in JSON messaging format for handling database operations and implemented a dynamic data grid that makes use of this JavaScript library for handling database operations asynchronously without page reloads using AJAX.

Technologies: XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, YUI

Built dashboard with live graphs

Designed and developed an administration dashboard with embedded real time graphs that dynamically update every minute without page reloads to show the current status of the users logged on to the system and the current memory and resource consumption in the system.

Technologies: XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, RRDTool

CodecX Technology, Inc., Milpitas, CA - Software Engineer

JUNE 2005 - JANUARY 2006

Built and maintained embedded web apps in network appliances.

Tech: PHP, XML, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Hackernews Clone: Built a Hackernews clone using React, Apollo, Prisma, graphql-yoga and node.js following one of the best online resources for learning GraphQL https://howtographql.com/